RESUME

Premananda Das

B-131, New Ashok Nagar, New Delhi E-mail: das prema@rediffmail.com

Phone: +91 9643994479

PROFILE

Experienced professional with over 14 years of proven success in the field of human resources. Demonstrated high level of energy and commitment to excellence to achieving departmental and organizational goals. Organized, efficient, detailed, with proven ability to plan, organize, implement, and complete tasks and project within constraints of deadlines. Relate extremely well to diverse staff and successfully developed methods for improving teamwork, productivity and administrative procedures.

EXPERIENCE

Post Held: Sr. Executive, MPS Ltd., Noida, UP – Sept. 2014 till now

Responsibilities and duties:

- Handling a team of production people (Composition, Quality Controllers, Editors, Art team).
- Giving page counts for billing and coordinating with project managers for the timely delivery of pages.
- Analyzing specs and client requirements for the project.
- Making shift and leave roasters.
- Coordinating with HR personnel for recruitment, leave, evaluation, transfer and hr related activities for production people.

<u>Post Held: Administrator (HR Dept.) Midmac Contracting Co WLL, Doha, Qatar 2010-2014</u> <u>Responsibilities and duties:</u>

- Providing complete administrative/secretarial support to the Human Resources Manager and other senior staff as required
- Responsible for input of transactional data into the HRMS, including new hires, leave, warnings, terminations, transfers, evaluations, pay rate changes etc.
- Preparing leave and final settlement of employees proceeding on leave/final dept.
- Preparing company ID card, salary certificate, experience certificates and other documents required by the employee.
- Organized personal files keeping all the documents of individual employees.

- Perform necessary data entry and quality assurance to maintain the integrity of HRMS data
- Providing data support and point-of-contact for all data needs within the team
- Managing the department correspondence (mail, faxes and courier material)
- Liase with candidates or employees for various HR related queries when required
- Maintains good relationship with all members of the Human Resources team and coordinate well with all staff of the company.
- Follow-up and keep abreast of changes to internal policies and procedures and maintaining a tracking file and reviewing routine audit checks
- Performing various other duties and activities as assigned by HR Manager within the physical constraints of the job.
- Supports special projects and completes other responsibilities associated with the position as may be appropriate.

<u>Post Held: Asst. Administrator, Midmac Contracting Co WLL, Doha, Qatar-2007-2014</u> Responsibilities and duties:

- Professionally and promptly handle day day project administrative affairs.
- Preparation of Labour Histogram, Time Sheets, Site Diary, Variation Log Sheet, tracking of driver duties. etc.
- Looking up for office stationeries and consumables.
- Assigning jobs for site securities, maintenance staffs, drivers and office boys
- · Maintaining shift and leave rosters for site staff and coordinating with HR dept. for that
- Arrangements of business trips for the Managers and Engineers for various works like
 Factory visits for procurement of materials
- Checking driver log sheet and approving overtimes, time sheets
- Checking and sending labour/staff time sheets to the wages department for monthly salary, leave and final settlements
- Coordinate and schedule meetings with projects management on various issues
- Filing all the documents required for site, i.e., building permit, road block permit, water, electric bills etc
- Sending messages by E-mail, Fax
- Handling Site Petty Cash
- Coordinating with admin dept. for the Q-Tel, Kahramaa, Gate passes, etc. for the smooth running of the projects
- Follow-up and coordination with Admin dept. for the visa related issues for the employees
- Liaison with the other departments / staff
- Completing the work entrusted in time

- Committed to HSE requirements and all applicable legislations and contractual requirements affecting the HSE activities at project site and administrative offices
- Prioritizing the work schedule in terms of its urgency / importance and other aspects

Post Held: Executive, QC, Aptara Corporation, New Delhi – 2002-2007 Responsibilities and duties:

- Proof read thoroughly the books and journals of Kluwer Academic Publishers, and McGraw Hill Higher Education.
- Coordinating with Project Managers, PPC team, Editors, Art team, and Compositors for the timely delivery of pages.
- Allocating and distributing jobs in the department for smooth running of projects.
- Handling client e-mails and couriers.
- Preparing leave and shift rosters.
- Preparing and updating job log sheet, giving page counts to the billing department.
- Managing in and out register of employees, night shift allowance sheet, office consumables and various other works.

EDUCATIONAL QUALIFICATION

B.Sc. from Utkal University, Orissa

Diploma in Computers from LCC, Orissa

Fire Warden Training from Doha Industrial Safety and Security Institute

PERSONAL DETAILS

Father's Name: Mr. Baishnab Charan Das

Permanent Address: Vill - Ghigidia, P.O. Barua, Dist. Kendrapara, Orissa, India

Date of Birth: 12-04-1978

Religion: Hindu

Marital Status: Married

Languages Known: English, Hindi, Oriya

PASSPORT DETAILS

Passport No. G0700016 Issue Date: 03-01-2007 Expiry Date: 02-01-2017

Issue Place: Bhubaneswar, Orissa